XIAOHONG LIU

Phone: 1-(613) 276 3521 **Email**: liux173@mcmaster.ca

Website: xiaohongliu.ca/ LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/xiaohong-liu/ Github: github.com/proteus1991

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I'm a forth-year Ph.D. candidate at McMaster University. My research direction aims at video and image processing based on deep learning, especially in restoration, classification, recognition, and manipulation/abnormal detection. As an AI researcher, I'm always energetic and enthusiastic to implement cutting-edge AI techniques and have already published several papers on the top journal and conference (e.g., TIP and ICCV). In order to gain industrial experience, I have interned in several companies to develop practical AI products.

EDUCATION

Hamilton, Canada McMaster University Jan. 2018 - Current Doctor of Philosophy in Electrical and Computer Engineering **Michigan State University** East Lansing, U.S. May 2020 - Dec. 2020 Visiting Scholar, supervised by Dr. Xiaoming Liu **University of Ottawa** Ottawa, Canada Master of Applied Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering Sep. 2014 - Dec. 2016 Southwest Jiaotong University Chengdu, China Bachelor of Engineering in Telecommunication Sep. 2010 - Jul. 2014

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python: 4-year programming experience to implement cutting-edge techniques in computer vision.

Matlab: 6-year programming experience. Proficient in APIs for image processing.

AI framework: Proficient in PyTorch/Torch and Tensorflow. Good knowledge in Caffe.

Linux: Use Ubuntu in daily developing. Familiar with commonly used Linux commands. Able to use SSH to access remote servers.

Able to write bash scripts for batch processing.

Others: Git/Github, Agile Development, C/C++ and etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM May 2019 – Aug. 2019

IoT & AI Developer - Coop

Toronto, Canada

• Interned in IBM as an IoT & AI developer and responsible for two projects: 1) time series forecasting that infers bathroom footfalls based on sensor-collected data to make Bell office-building intelligent in sense of setting dynamic cleanup schedules; 2) open-set face recognition, where open-set means there might be an unknown face showing up in testing. 99% recognition accuracy has been achieved in this system.

Cymax Group

Research Intern

Jan. 2019 – Jun. 2019

Burnaby, Canada

• Interned in Cymax Group as an AI/Machine researcher and responsible for developing a neural network that can predict the optimal price-cost trade-off for each selling product to maximize the chance of winning the competition against other companies in Amazon. Specifically, a novel 1D convolutional neural network was designed that enables to use long-range historical sales data to produce the winning strategy.

Car Media 2.0 Apr. 2018 – Dec. 2018

Research Intern

Burlington, Canada

• Interned in Car Media 2.0 Dev team and responsible for developing an automated deep alpha-matting tool for Vehicle image. This tool recognizes vehicles from image background without any human intervention.

COMPUTER VISION COMPETITIONS

- Won a Runner-Up Award (2nd place) in AIM 2020 Challenge on Learned ISP (in conjuction with ECCV 2020).
- Ranked the 3rd place in AIM 2020 Challenge on Efficient Super-Resolution (in conjunction with ECCV 2020).
- Ranked the 3rd place in NTIRE 2020 Challenge on Image Demoireing (in conjunction with CVPR 2020).

Google Scholar: 150+ citations. *: co-first authors, †: the corresponding author.

Journal:

- 1. **Liu, X.**, Chen, L., Wang W., and Zhao, J.[†] Robust Multi-Frame Super-Resolution Based on Spatially Weighted Half-Quadratic Estimation and Adaptive BTV Regularization. *IEEE Transactions on Image Processing*, 2018. PDF
- 2. **Liu, X.**[†], Shi, K., Wang, Z., and Chen, J. Exploit Camera Raw Data for Video Super-Resolution via Hidden Markov Model Inference. *IEEE Transactions on Image Processing*, 2021. PDF
- 3. Shi, Z., Liu, X.[†], Shi, K., Dai, L., and Chen, J. Video Frame Interpolation via Generalized Deformable Convolution, *IEEE Transactions on Multimedia*, 2021. PDF
- 4. Wang, W., Hu, J., **Liu, X.**[†], Zhao, J., and Chen, J. Single image super-resolution based on multi-scale structure and nonlocal smoothing. *To appear in EURASIP Journal on Image and Video Processing*.
- 5. **Liu, X.**, Shi, Z., Wu, Z., and Chen, J[†]. GridDehazeNet+: An Enhanced Multi-Scale Network with Intra-Task Knowledge Transfer for Single Image Dehazing. *Under reviewed in IEEE Transactions on Image Processing*. PDF
- 6. Shi, Z., Li, C., Dai, L., **Liu, X.**[†], Chen, J., and Davidson, T. N. Learning for Unconstrained Space-Time Video Super-Resolution. *Under reviewed in IEEE Transactions on Multimedia*. PDF

Conference:

- 1. **Liu, X.**, and Zhao, J. Robust Multi-Frame Super-Resolution with Adaptive Norm Choice and Difference Curvature based BTV Regularization. *IEEE Global Conference on Signal and Information Processing (GlobalSIP)*, 2017. PDF
- 2. Zhou, Y., Liu, X., and Zhao, J. Video Super-Resolution via Dynamic Local Filter Network. *IEEE Global Conference on Signal and Information Processing (GlobalSIP)*, 2018. PDF
- 3. Shi, K., Liu, X., Guo, X., Lin, J., Alrabeiah, M., Liu, H., and Chen, J. Image Retrieval via Canonical Correlation Analysis. *16th Canadian Workshop on Information Theory (CWIT)*, 2019. PDF
- 4. Liu, X.*, Ma, Y.*, Shi, Z., and Chen, J. GridDehazeNet: Attention based Multi-Scale Network for Image Dehazing. *IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2019. PDF
- 5. **Liu, X.**, Kong, L., Zhou, Y., Zhao, J., and Chen, J. End-to-End Trainable Video Super-Resolution Based on a New Mechanism for Implicit Motion Estimation and Compensation. *IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)*, 2020. PDF
- Dai, L.*, Liu, X.*, Li, C., and Chen J. AWNet: Attentive Wavelet Network for Image ISP. European Conference on Computer Vision Workshop (ECCVW), 2020. PDF
- 7. **Liu, X.**, Liu, Y., Chen J., and Liu, X. PSCC-Net: Progressive Spatio-Channel Correlation Network for Image Manipulation Detection and Localization. *Under reviewed in IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2021. PDF
- 8. Dai, L.*, Song, X.*, **Liu, X.***, Li, C., Shi, Z., Chen, J., and Brooks, M. Enabling Trimap-Free Image Matting with a Frequency-Guided Saliency-Aware Network via Joint Learning. *Under reviewed in IEEE International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2021.

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

- Joint the executive team in McMaster AI Society as a senior project manager.
- Journal review: IEEE Transactions on Image Processing, IEEE Transactions on Multimedia, IEEE Transactions on Broadcasting, IEEE Transactions on Circuits and Systems for Video Technology, IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems.
- Conference review: PG 2020, WACV 2020, ICCV 2021.

Awards

- Won the 2019-20 Borealis AI Global Fellowship award (one of the 10 nominees in Canada!). Details can be found here.
- Awarded an Alexander Graham Bell Canada Graduate Scholarship-Doctoral from Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC). This is the best scholarship for Ph.D. students in Canada.
- Awarded an Ontario Graduate Scholarship. This is a merit-based scholarship provided by the Province of Ontario in Canada.
- · Awarded an McMaster Graduate Scholarship.